Move over Victoria sponge cake.
维多利亚海绵蛋糕靠边站吧。
Modern bakeries are trending – delivering fresh flavours and celebrating independence.
现代面包店正流行起来——提供新鲜口味并崇尚独立精神。
Hybrid creations are becoming increasingly common.
混合创意产品正变得越来越常见。
On a trip to the bakery, you could come across a cronut or a duffin, and Coyle's Bakeshop in Seattle, USA sells cretzels – a cross between a croissant and a pretzel.
去面包店时，你可能会遇到可颂甜甜圈或松饼甜甜圈，美国西雅图的科伊尔烘焙坊还出售椒盐可颂卷——它是可颂和椒盐卷饼的混合体。
They're made of croissant dough, shaped like a pretzel and sprinkled with sea salt.
它们由可颂面团制成，做成椒盐卷饼的形状，并撒上海盐。
Popular too are cakesicles, crumbled sponge mixed with frosting on a stick, and donut holes, a small round piece of donut dough that could fill the hole in a typical donut, hence the name.
同样受欢迎的还有蛋糕棒（将碎海绵蛋糕与糖霜混合后放在棍子上）和甜甜圈洞（一小块圆形甜甜圈面团，恰好能填满传统甜甜圈的洞，因而得名）。
And it's not just creations that are changing – new ingredients are taking hold too.
不仅仅是产品在变化——新的原料也在流行。
At the London-based bakery British Patagonia, you can tuck into a peanut, caramel and miso cookie – miso is typically a savoury Asian flavour.
在伦敦的英国巴塔哥尼亚面包店，你可以品尝到花生、焦糖和味噌饼干——味噌通常是一种咸鲜的亚洲风味。
While there you could also have the nutty 'sticky pistachio' – a bake made from pistachio paste and pistachio ganache.
在那里，你还可以吃到坚果味的"粘稠开心果"——一种由开心果酱和开心果奶油夹心制成的烘焙品。
Activated charcoal sourdough bread can frequently be found in bakeries too.
活性炭酸面团面包在面包店里也很常见。
Aside from being strikingly black, adding charcoal makes no change to the flavour of the bread because it's essentially tasteless and odourless.
除了颜色令人惊讶地黑，添加木炭并不会改变面包的味道，因为它基本上是无味无臭的。
And turmeric lattes are also commonplace these days, if you fancy a healthy drink alongside a bite to eat.
如今姜黄拿铁也很常见，如果你想在吃点东西的同时喝一杯健康饮品的话。
Bakeries are also embracing dietary inclusivity and sustainability.
面包店也在拥抱饮食包容性和可持续性。
Pink Lane Bakery in Newcastle delivers bakes to customers via electric van and cargo bikes, and their website states they take care to ensure their packaging is 'as recyclable as possible'.
纽卡斯尔的粉巷面包店通过电动面包车和货运自行车向顾客配送烘焙食品，他们的网站声称他们努力确保包装"尽可能可回收"。
Consumers are increasingly choosing to buy more local and unique products by turning to independent bakeries.
消费者越来越多地通过转向独立面包店来选购更具本地特色和独特性的产品。
According to industry magazine Food and Beverage Business, 'This preference for artisanal options has driven the growth of independent bakery sales, which are expected to rise by 25.3% this year, reaching £1.6 billion.'
据行业杂志《食品与饮料商业》报道，"这种对手工制品的偏好推动了独立面包店销售额的增长，预计今年将增长25.3%，达到16亿英镑。"
So, try a new flavour and shop local.
所以，尝试新口味，在当地购物吧。
Who knows what new trend is around the corner.
谁知道下一个新趋势即将到来呢。